Are you fed up with the American
lifestyle? Are you tired of getting your
food in a freezer covered in plastic?
Are you tired of chemtrails in the air
and water that tastes like fluoride? I
was, too. That's why I moved to Costa
Rica with my family. Right now, I'm
going to walk you around and show you
how we're living here. We have a 4-acre
homestead here. This is all ornamental
ginger. It's so tall it forms a tunnel.
My dream is to grow all of my own food
right here on my own property. That way,
no man can control my life. These are
our lobster cons. They're a lot like
crayfish, but they get about 12 in
inches long. Absolutely delicious and
they grow year-round. We have six ponds
here and this one has tilapia in it.
These are our protein sources. We have
chicken for eggs, we have tilapia in
that pond, and we have goats down here.
One goat, two goats, and a little baby
goat. His name is Billy.
Yeah, bee in Spanish. That's right, bee.
A couple more months and this girl will
be ready to milk. We went with goats cuz
they're a lot smaller than cows, they
stink a lot less, and the milk is
supposedly better for you. Got a
pineapple going and those are our guinea
fowl. They're a lot like chicken, but
cooler cuz they lay rock hard eggs and
they eat fleas and ticks, and they also
act like guard dogs. They'll let you
know if any stranger shows up on your
property. Way better than a chicken. We
have about 30 cacao trees. This is what
chocolate comes from. It's known as the
food of the gods and it tastes nothing
like chocolate. It's actually white and
milky on the inside with a texture that
only a woman would love. Coconut's are
my personal favorite. I love to take a
coconut, cut the top off, and squeeze
two fresh oranges in there to make a
cold drink every day. Plantains are a
staple in our diet. We have plantains
for days and they taste really good
fried up with a little bit of oil.
All these are plantains.
This is a fully organic farm. We don't
use any chemicals or pesticides and this
lemongrass is what we use for bug
repellent. We also have citronella
growing,
but this lemongrass smells great. It
keeps the bugs off you with no chemicals
put out in the atmosphere.
You don't want to be eating chemicals
when you can have lemongrass. We
actually have cotton growing as well.
They use this for chicken bedding and
clothing and all kinds of stuff. I use
it to put in my ears so I can't hear
Alex complaining at me. This is guava
fruit. It has a creamy soft texture.
Really sweet, but you got to beat the
birds to them. That's the only problem.
Everything here is edible. It's a
literal food forest. We don't use
traditional seasonings. Everything is
flavored with something right out of the
garden. We have cilantro, we have
peppers. I love the garlic. This is my
little coffee tree. You can see it
starting to sprout right here. Pretty
soon we're going to have coffee right
off the stem. This is Jose, my first
Tico employee. He is a legend at growing
things and knows everything there is to
know about planting stuff in the ground.
This is an unnecessarily large leaf that
Alex uses to fan me during the heat of
the day. This is malanga. It's like a
Costa Rican potato. We have it growing
everywhere. This is a staple in our
diet. It's a good carbohydrate. Papaya
trees. We have a whole bunch of them
here. I absolutely love papaya and look
how many we have growing in the
distance.
Yeah, man. Literal food forest. We're
currently starting our first garden.
This is more malanga, cilantro and
lettuce and spinach and a whole bunch of
other stuff that I don't even know the
name of because I'm a stupid white man
living in Costa Rica. We have a whole
lot of plant life here, but there's also
some plant death, which also turns back
into life. We're using this mango tree
that fell to build our little casita in
the back. This is my Costa Rican
sawmill.
It's a grill.
This thing works great. We have milled
this mango down and it's a live edge
that we're using for counter tops and
tables and benches. There's a cross cut
section for my table and here's a bench
seat with a matching groove. Tell me
that ain't going to be fire. This is the
current construction zone. We have a
whole bunch of fresh cut cedar and
laurel that's been drying here and we're
building a little love nest in the backs
for me and Alex. This is going to be my
kitchen. I teak on the walls, corteza
for the window sills, cedar for the trim
and I'm not going to put any clear coat
on it.
I want to smell fresh wood, not
chemicals. I left a hole in the concrete
to grow a tree, and a super rare voodoo
lily popped up on its own. Talk about
the Little Shop of Horrors living in
your house. This is my bedroom. Just
listen for a second.
Could you wake up to that every morning?
I built everything myself, all out of
wood, including my door lock.
And this is my backyard.
Just wow.
Monkeys and toucans and hummingbirds all
day long. I handcrafted my seat
with my little tree restaurant right
here. This is my happy place. But we
really don't need this casita cuz we
have a massive main house on the front.
When we got here, we had a bad rat
problem, so we got some cats. Now we
have a bad cat problem, and the cats
will get in your house worse than the
rats. Plus, the girls like cats, so
they're not as easy to kill as rats, and
I don't know what to do with six cats
running around the place. Anybody want a
free cat? Got them in Costa Rica. This
is the prep area for the house. As you
can see, photos for days. This is where
I wash my laundry. This is where we prep
food.
This is where we put trash. There is no
trash service here, so I'm trying to
figure out a creative way to use it.
This is the kitchen, the heart of the
house. Kids are cooking. We've got
receipts spread out. It's a normal life.
Not really. I'm normal. This is a Costa
Rican shower and a typical Costa Rican
water heater. Most people are terrified
of having electrical tape wires in their
shower, but nobody's died here yet.
Completely safe. This is the only
air-conditioned room in the whole house.
So we keep the old books and Bibles and
computers in here because the humidity
damaged them. We're in the process of
starting a digital library with a bunch
of old occult knowledge that has been
lost to history, and so we have to keep
it safe. It's the only reason we use air
conditioning is to preserve history.
It's actually cold in here.
This is a three-bedroom house, and the
upstairs room is probably my favorite.
It's been taken by my 15-year-old
daughter. She's kind of like the boss
hog of the upstairs. Oh, yes. Got to
love a 15-year-old girl. This is the
best room in the house because of the
air flow and the breeze at night.
Absolutely fantastic. You really do not
need air conditioning. I don't know why
the world is so obsessed with
recirculated air. This is where we store
stuff. All the cabinets are made out of
teak. We don't even have enough clothes
to put in here, so we just got a bunch
of random junk piled up. I mean, I
really don't wear a shirt and uh maybe
the same pair of shorts every day.
Handmade alpaca by some natives. Higher,
huh? We have an entire great room here
that we're not doing anything with. One
day I think this will be used for
electrical classes and seminars, maybe
group yoga. Life is pretty good here,
but I'm still building. This is my
off-grid solar system, some big battery.
I have 60 kW of storage, not bad for a
house that uses like 30 kW a month. This
is how I'm living right now, completely
off-grid, sweating when it's hot, no hot
water, food from the earth. Plan is to
build a renewable energy center here so
other people can come experience the
off-grid life because the world needs
this right now. Everybody needs to be
fully self-supporting and autonomous. We
need to know how to get our food from
the earth, our energy from the ground,
and our water from the river, not from
the store, a bottle, and a plant, cuz
that's reality. Everything comes from
the earth and we've been living out of
harmony with it. And even if I'm the
only one taking a stand, I'm going to
make this place called reality so you
can come here and experience it
yourself.
Pura vida.